Alexander O'Neill

Software Engineer Freeport ME (207) 272-8676 alexander.oneill75@gmail.com

GitHub (https://github.com/alexo75) | LinkedIn (https://www.linkedin.com/in/alexandermoneill/)

Summary:

Computer Science undergraduate with a diverse skill set and an aptitude for learning new software tools. Proficiency in React.js framework, Python, Java, with some experience with Elixir/Phoenix LiveView, C#, mySQL, and Machine Learning tools (such as TensorFlow, Pytorch, Pandas). As of January 2024, I am on track to finish up my bachelors degree in May at USM.

Education:

 Bachelor of Science in Computer Science University of Southern Maine Current (expected graduation: May 2024)

 Associate's degree in Computer Science Southern Maine Community College, Portland, ME May 2022

Experience:

 Receptionist, Prentice Hospitality Organization Summer 2023 - Present

- Monitor parking, answering calls for the company.
- Web Developer Intern, QueerlyMe

Summer 2023

- Developed a user-friendly website using Elixir/Phoenix Liveview.
- Collaborated closely with the design team to ensure seamless design-to-development transition.
- IT/IS Internship, MaineHealth, Norway, ME

May 2022 - Aug 2022

- o Resolved technical issues via the ticket system.
- Shadowed help desk; acquired troubleshooting and customer service skills.
- **Telecommunication Technician,** *E.S. Boulos*, Portland, ME 2016-2019
 - Managed data networks across various locations; focused more on hardware installations

Skills:

- Programming & Web: Java, Python (machine learning), React.js framework, React Native, HTML, C#, JSP/Servlets, CSS, Elixir/Phoenix Liveview
- Tools & Systems: GitHub, mySQL, postgreSQL, Google Colab
- Frameworks & Patterns: MVC Architecture, Software Design Patterns